Antonio Toscano

5965 Stafford Ave, Huntington Park CA 90255 • (323) 997-7165 • antonio toscano80@yahoo.com

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Recent graduate seeking career opportunities in IT support. Reliable problem solver and team leader with experience working in the field of IT for over 6 years. Insightful communicator with a knack for solving technical issues and improving processes.

PROFESSIONAL AND TECHNICAL SKILL

Leadership • Written and Oral Communications • Bilingual (English and Spanish) Microsoft Server 2016 • Proxmox • CentOS • Ubuntu CSS • HTML • MySQL • Apache • LAMP • Linux • PHP • Microsoft Server 2008 r2 • CentOS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Evocative Data Centers *merger acquisitions with Cyberverse Data Center Technician

Downtown Los Angeles, CA

June 2018 – Present (1 year)

- Technical Support Reviews provisioning tickets, change, install, troubleshoot data communication systems & servers. Follows ticketing system and verify and authenticate client requests. Follows clients orders, test fiber optic & ethernet cables.
- Analysis and Evaluation Works closely with Data Center Managers and technical team to ensure business and technical aspects are met. Maintains expert knowledge and collaborate with Systems Administrators, Data Center Managers.
- Communications and Customer Service Reviews monitoring systems, responds to calls and client ticket request in a timely manner, troubleshoot, escalate issues when needed.

Woodland Hills, CA Hexpose

IT Network Management Administrator

May 2015 – Present (4 years)

- Technical Support Provides IT support to Administrative Directors in order to facilitate SAILS Group operations. Installs and manages VOIP phones, printers, and switches. Troubleshoot & upgraded desktop workstations to increase workflow.
- Analysis and Evaluation Develops and implements educational programs for staff and Administrative Directors. Analyzed costs and benefits of installing solar panels and presented recommendations to management; once installed, energy costs were significantly
- Communications and Customer Service Actively communicates with Facility Administrators to schedule appointments and solve issues quickly. Travels to remote locations across Southern California on a monthly basis.

Cyberverse **Downtown Los Angeles, CA** Data Center Technician June 2015 – June 2018 (3 Years)

Technical Support - Reviewed work orders to move, change, install, repair, or remove data communications equipment such as servers or cables. Disassembled equipment and inspects and tests wiring to locate and repair problems. Planned layout and installation of data communication equipment. Measured, cut, and installed wires, Ethernet, and fiber optic cables.

- Analysis and Evaluation Maintained expert product knowledge in order to better anticipate, diagnose, and resolve customer problems as well as develop and implement effective solutions. Inspected technical difficulties and systemic issues and provides insights for process improvement opportunities.
- Communications and Customer Service Collaborated closely with cross-functional teammates from all backgrounds to achieve project goals. Researches and compiles material and prepares detailed reports. Utilizes Microsoft software suite, including Word, Excel, and PowerPoint to record, maintain, and retrieve data, and track plans, schedules, and status. Serves as liaison between customer service and technical teams, ensuring customer needs are correctly prioritized and met.

EDUCATION

California State University Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA

B.S., Computer Information Systems / Opt Information Technology

June 2016

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Association of Latino Professionals for America, Los Angeles Professional Chapter Director of Information Technology

Los Angeles, CA July 2016 - Present

- Develops and updates content for the Los Angeles professional chapter website
- Coordinates website migration activities with the CIO and Chapter President.
- Notifies and advises ALPFA members about upcoming opportunities and events.

Students for Progress, CSULA

Director of Public Relations

Los Angeles, CA

December 2013 – December 2014

- Co-founded organization committed to providing students with personal and professional skill development opportunities.
- Planned and booked guest speakers for weekly meetings.
- Attended networking events to establish relationships with recruiters.
- Created workshops and searched for internship opportunity for members
- Developed the organizations website using the University's web servers.

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonio-toscano